

Mikolaj Semeniuk

Email: m.semeniuk@icloud.com Telephone: +48 533 838 844 Github: https://github.com/mikolajsemeniuk/ StackOverflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/ 13947931/mikolaj-semeniuk

Skills

- Very good knowledge of Java version 8 and its data structures, including Optional, Streams and Regex expressions
- Very good knowledge of Spring Framework and Spring Security
- Very good command of C# version 5.0 and its data structures, inter alia, structures IEnumerable, ICollection, OneOf, LINQ, await/async, Regex and Reflection
- Very good command of .NET framework and Entity Framework, Migrations, Identity Server 4 and MassTransit
- Very good knowledge of Python version 3.7, especially in data analysis and building models to perform predictions, classification, learning about data structure, data tagging, generating synthetic data using Sklearn, Pytorch, Tensorflow and Keras
- Very good knowledge of **Docker** and **Kubernetes**
- Very good knowledge of Linux and **Bash** (I use Linux every day)
- Very good knowledge of Windows **Forms**
- Very good knowledge of VueJS and AngularJS frameworks, frontend application state management, dynamic data sending, displaying API requests
- Very good knowledge of NodeJS with Typescript, ExpressJS, NestJS and **TypeORM**
- Very good knowledge of Go with Go-Gin, GORM, GRPC
- Very good knowledge of the practices of writing Clean Code Uncle Bob's, SOLID principles, DDD, TDD, YARNI, DRY, KISS and knowledge of design patterns such as CQRS, CQS, MVC, SOA
- databases such as: SQL Server with **SQL Queries, Stored Procedures,** Triggers, Indexes and MySQL, **PostgresSQL**

Very good knowledge of relational

databases such as: MongoDB, Redis, poor Apache Cassandra

Very good knowledge of non-relational

- Ability to write unit tests and tests using the **Selenium** framework
- language

Very good knowledge of of

Very good command of the English

environments such as: Visual Studio, Intellij, Visual Studio Code, Google Colab, Jupyter notebook oraz Conda I am currently an extramural 3rd year student in **Data Science**. I have almost **three years** of experience in developing web applications mainly in languages such as Java and C# and data analysis using **Python**.

In my spare time I read books about data analysis, especially about unsupervised learning, and I learn new languages and upload projects to GitHuba, Google Colab, I also participate in StackOverflow.

Apart from my CV, please also check my GitHub

Experience

Ernst & Young

I was employed as a junior analyst, but the scope of my duties varied depending on the projects to which I was assigned. Below are the projects and responsibilities.

Implementation of new functionalities and modernization of the internal 2021.09portal of the British insurer. I was responsible for: 2021.01

- Adding new functionalities contained on the portal: Jira and Confluence in accordance with the **Scrum** methodology
- Communicating with Business Analysts and Scrum Master from Great Britain in English
- Implementation of **API** endpoints using **Spring Web** compatible with the Controller, Service, Repository pattern
- Implementing user rights and roles and generating authentication tokens using OAuth2 and Spring Security
- Configuration of communication between **micro services** using **RabbitMQ**
- Implementation of writes and reads to the **SQL Server** relational database
- Sending and receiving SOAP and REST requests
- Upload files using requests
- Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to the repository via Git version control versions, and Azure Dev Ops
- Writing unit tests
- Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger
- Writing and reading technical documentation

Data analysis for EY internal EY business process recognition tool. I was 2020.12-2020.11 responsible for:

Cleaning and preparation of collected data

- Data analysis using **python 3.7**, **sklearn**, **pandas**, **numpy**, **matplotib** and **seaborn**
- Feature detection with sklearn algorithms such as PCA, K-means and K **Nearest Neighbors**
- Building data structure learning models using Pytorch and tensorflow such as Autoencoders

Implementation of new functionalities and modernization of the internal 2020.11-2020.05 portal of the company from the United States dealing with the production of prostheses. I was responsible for:

in accordance with the **Scrum** methodology

Adding new functionalities contained on the portal: Jira and Confluence

• Communicating with **Business Analysts** and **Scrum Master** from the United States in English

• Implementation of API endpoints using Asp Net Core Mvc compatible

- with the **Controller, Service, IService** pattern Implementing user rights and roles and generating authentication tokens
- using OAuth2 and Asp Net Identity and Identity Server 4
- Communication configuration between microservices using RabbitMQ and **MassTransit**
- Implementation of writes and reads to the SQL Server relational database and **Redis** NoSQL database
- Sending and receiving GRAPHQL requests using the Hot Chocolate
- Upload files using requests

framework and **REST** requests

- Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to the repository via **Git** version control versions, and **Azure Dev Ops**
- Writing unit tests with xUnit and Moq
- Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger Writing and reading technical documentation
- Implementation of an internal invoice settlement portal for a company from

responsible for: Adding new functionalities in accordance with the Scrum methodology

Communicating with client and Scrum Master

Poznań using the NodeJS language and the Express.js framework. I was

- File validation in terms of business logic
- Uploading, reading and saving a large number of files (mainly excel files)

on the server

- Sending emails to customers who are in arrears with payment of their
- debts Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger
- Writes and reads to the PostgresSQL relational database
- Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to
- the repository via Git version control versions, and GitLab

I worked as a full-stack developer using technologies such as PHP with Laravel framework and JavaScript with frameworks, AngularJS and VueJS

LastLevel

2020.05-2020.02

Implementation of new functionalities on the front and backend side in 2019.11online stores and blogs as well as data analysis for these portals. I was 2019.02

responsible for: Maintaining application state with Vue Store and Angular NGRX Sending REST requests using Vue Axios and Angular HttpClient to the

- backend
- Generating mobile and desktop applications from JavaScript code using Electron and Apache Cordova
- Dynamic display of backend data Implementation of new artwork using VueJS and AngularJS, and
- compatible with the MVC pattern Implementing user rights and roles and generating authentication tokens

• Implementation of **API** endpoints using the **Laravel** framework

bootstrap, material, tailwind css frameworks and SCSS

- using Laravel Passport
- Sending emails to users

Implementation of writes and reads to the MySQL referential database

Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger

 Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to the repository via Git version control versions, and GitLab, and RedMine

Neighbors from **Sklearn**

 Data analysis using the Python language and algorithms: PCA, Logistic Regression, Random Forests, K- Means, K Nearest

Education

Present-

2019.10

Warsaw School of Computer Science In 2019, I started my studies at the Warsaw School of Computer Science in extramural mode, specializing in Data Science. I am currently in my third year and I am starting an engineering thesis about generating synthetic data

PyTorch/Scikit

GRPC

Some of my university projects were:

• Writing artificial neuronal network from scratch using **Numpy** in **C#** language • Creating unsupervised nlp algorithms/models to classify text in python and

by the Deep Belief Network model (Deep Belief Network).

Creating CQRS in C# using Identity Server 4 and RabbitMQ

• Creating application based on client and server using Golang, GORM and

Creating application using Go with Go-Gin, GORM and ReactJS

European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016. on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal

data and on the free movement of such data and the repeal of Directive 95/46 / EC (GDPR).